Nigel Doheny Junior Full Stack Developer

nigel.doheny93@gmail.com• +353 085 185 2187 • Ireland github • linkedin •

Executive Summary

Junior Software Developer with a Diploma in Full stack Software Development from the Code Institute. Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python. I have 15 years experience in Customer Service and hospitality. I am a valuable team-player with strong communication skills and effective problem solving ability. I am eager to gain entry into the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can grow and contribute!

Education

March 2022 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland -

(Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland)

Technical Skillset

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python
Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres
Frameworks: Django, jQuery, Bootstrap

Version Control: Git, Github

Portfolio projects

- 1. Cult Called Man https://github.com/ExcellentWish/first html css ci project
- Faith in Us E-commerce site for a handmade soap shop, which offers a variety of eco/skin friendly soaps.
 Technologies Used HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap, JavaScript, Python, Django framework, Postgres DB, Stripe API for payments and AWS for hosting media. GitHub https://github.com/karenstanton/ms4_faith
- 3. Faith in Us E-commerce site for a handmade soap shop, which offers a variety of eco/skin friendly soaps.

 Technologies Used HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap, JavaScript, Python, Django framework, Postgres DB, Stripe API for payments and AWS for hosting media. GitHub https://github.com/karenstanton/ms4 faith
- 4. Faith in Us E-commerce site for a handmade soap shop, which offers a variety of eco/skin friendly soaps.
 Technologies Used HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap, JavaScript, Python, Django framework, Postgres DB, Stripe API for payments and AWS for hosting media. GitHub https://github.com/karenstanton/ms4 faith
- 5. Faith in Us E-commerce site for a handmade soap shop, which offers a variety of eco/skin friendly soaps.

 Technologies Used HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap, JavaScript, Python, Django framework, Postgres DB, Stripe API for payments and AWS for hosting media. GitHub https://github.com/karenstanton/ms4 faith

Work Experience

March 2019–Present

Emerald contact centre, Customer Ambassador

Remote, Waterford

- Work at helpdesk, Provide technical support to customers
- We use RDP for advantage. VMware Horizon Client
- Use the Advantage CRM systems

2017 -2019

Prr Reilly/ Euro Car Parts: Warehouse supervisor

Galway and Waterford

- K8 systems and AS400 for Stock control
- K8 System had system for despatch controller

2016 - 2017

Subway

Tuam RD, Galway

- POS System
- Stock control System

2015-2016

Applegreen Chopstix

Galway

- POS System
- Stock control System

2014-2015

SuperValu

Ballybane, Galway

- POS System
- Stock control System

2009-2014

SuperValu

Ballyraggot, Kilkenny

- POS System
- Stock control System.

Certifications

- Coursera -Google IT Support https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificate/ZU3F3DP93T4X
- Tefl 120 hours advance qualification

Interests/Additional Information

- Participation in Code Institute Hackathon: Love is in the Air I was a scrum master on this collaborative project.
- Participation in Code Institute Hackathon: Happy Holidays! We placed 2nd in this collaborative project.
- I attend regular 'women in tech' networking events.
- I am an avid nature blogger, regularly posting and updating my blog 'nature in mind'
- Fluent Spanish, Fluent English, Beginner German
- I'm a Community Lead in the CI Slack Community.